

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER · FULL STACK

Desamparados, San Jose, Costa Rica

□ (+506) 88-61-59-58 | **□** r0ch1bryan@gmail.com | **□** bryan-romero-chinchilla-20b3001b5

Summary

Developer with +4 years of experience, with use of free technologies, where the first 2 years I have worked in Industrial technology environments, full stack development, SQL engines and database design, the last year training as DevOps, with the ability to work in a team and under pressure, with design and abstraction skills, leadership and discipline

Work Experience

Intel Corporation at Praxis

Heredia, Costa Rica

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - II

Jul 2022 - Sep 2023

- Building automation scripts in Python
- Use of different operating systems Red Hat Linux, Windows Server and platforms such as Servers, NUCs, virtual machines, controllers (Banino, TTK) for automated testing.
- Integration with Intel's various proprietary services for automated test results delivery

Cecropia Solutions Cartago, Costa Rica

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

April 2021 - April 2022

- · Created automated CI/CD pipelines on Bitbucket for a flask Python 3 app, with Bash script to rebuild the solution
- Built automated CI/CD pipelines on Azure DevOps for and C# .net applications with properties dependencies.
- · Balanced creation of docker containers, according to load tests, save resources with the developed mechanism
- MQTT IoT Broker: Mosquitto broker technology, Prometheus, Grafana dashboard with important metrics like numbers of clients connected and infrastructure health of the solution, Python and bash CLI app to automatically reconstruct the solution as a DevOps
- · Azure Data Bricks(PySpark) Python Book: Created Algorithm to Merge Data from Salesforce to Data Analysis

Unilever Belen, Costa Rica

FULL STACK DEVELOPER & TECH ANALYST

April 2019 - April 2021

- Design and implementation of an internal solution with Golang Monolithic centralized system for paperless operation and data analysis (OEE, giveaway, WO, MES, QMS).
- · Microservices in python for reporting system, on the captured data, and statistics reports by email.
- Multidisciplinary engineering IoT and Industrial automation projects.
- Industrial Machine eficiency improvement and savings with data analysis.
- Supervision and follow-up of improvement of the industrial network.
- Web server optimization to work on a low power network, use of NGINX to compress traffic, and use of web optimization guides improving load times
- · Creation of excel macros, to improve the spreadsheets used by the company, facilitate the work of line supervisors and process engineers.

Honors & Awards.

INTERNATIONAL

Finalist, Hackathon 19 - gestion financiera pública, organized by the International Monetary Fund and

San Jose, Costa

Ministerio de Hacienda

Rica

2017 **Participation**, International Space Apps Challenge, organized by NASA and the ITCR Cartago, Costa Rica

DOMESTIC

Cerificate, Libre Office, National Technical University
 Academic excellence, Certificate of recognition by C.T.P Mercedes Norte
 Heredia, Costa Rica

Education

Costa Rica Institute of Technology

San Jose, Costa Rica

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

BUSINESS IT TECHNICIAN AND HIGHSCHOOL DIPLOMA

Feb. 2017 - Current

C.T.P.Mercedes Norte

Heredia, Costa Rica

Feb. 2013 - Nov. 2015

• Software Development, Computer Equipment Maintenance, administrative Computer Environment, Computer Networks, IT

October 18, 2023 Bryan Romero · Résumé